<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 15:45:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Epidemic of Narcissism</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/narcissism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 15:45:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/narcissism/</guid>
      <description>I was born in the latter years of the 70&amp;rsquo;s, so when I was growing up in the 80&amp;rsquo;s, I remember a world very different from the one in 2024, some four decades later.
I remember a world where as a five-year-old foreign child living in a foreign country (USSR), my mom would send me to get bread from the bakery without worrying about anything happening to me. The bakery was far enough, perhaps over a kilometer, and the snow on the roadside nearly reaching my neck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆★★★★★★★★★: Diary of a Madman</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 14:47:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</guid>
      <description>Before reading a translated work, I often find as many translations as I can in order to choose the best. To me, the best means close to the original in both how words must have sounded in the original, but also rendering it in English in such a way that it should, by itself, have its own literary merits in English.
Translations of foreign novels rare rarely loyal but everytime I find a good translation, it confirms my hunch that the translator must be a writer and an artist of a high caliber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>★★★★★★★★★★: Eight Below Zero</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/eight_below/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 12:17:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/eight_below/</guid>
      <description>I finally got round to watching Eight Below Zero. And I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did.
This here is a movie unlike much of the recent garbage coming out of Hollywood. For starters, there is no profanity and no obscenities; the female lead is decently dressed, and there is no anti-religious agenda pushed through the movie. The movie is artless and pure, like the the huskies featuring in it.
Paul Walker (rest in peace, brother) brings his superb and realistic acting skills to the screen and it is clear that Walker is a dog-person and his affection for the huskies is real and unpretentious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackjack in C#</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/blackjackincs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:34:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/blackjackincs/</guid>
      <description>Some of you from Quora know that I am very pro-C#. But what has C# got that Java, C and C++ haven&amp;rsquo;t?
I guess the simplest possible answer is that C# is programmer-friendlier than the above three combined, carries most of their advantages and none of their disadvantages.
More importantly, C#, now in version 12 (as of November 2023) has many new goodies that will make development in C# pure joy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hackernews is a 1984</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 11:39:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</guid>
      <description>I occasionally read Y Combinator&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Hackernews&amp;rsquo; but each time I do, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded how it resembles Winston&amp;rsquo;s world in the novel 1984.
My visits are programming related; I want to know what new developments have been occurring in the programming world. Occasionally it will also serve as a news aggregator in general. To be fair, to this end, it serves a useful niche, and I will continue visiting the site for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APL is for the intelligent</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:28:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</guid>
      <description>Why is APL the language of the future, even though it is roughly 50 years old? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t it take off like C did? To answer this, we need to delve into probability and intelligence.
The problem with probability is that things that seem non-random or planned may actually be random (Tarasov, 1990), whereas things that seem random, may, sometimes be deterministic or an outcome of some emergent state (where the interaction of several elements and factors causes a new state to emerge: for instance, poverty is one such fuzzy emergent state).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆: Tears of joke: marginal functionalism</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:22:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</guid>
      <description>Did you understand the title of this essay? Probably not. Neither would I have understood, to be frank, were I not the author. That&amp;rsquo;s because when I was coming up with a title for this essay, which, in my mind, arose as an allergic reaction to the garbage that David Foster Wallace&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;The Infinite Jest&amp;rdquo; is, I was sort of trying to convey the idea that I was going to write an essay about the fact that some people among us are merely marginally functional&amp;ndash;functional enough to be considered legally sane&amp;ndash;but otherwise are actually seriously mentally ill, and that, this was a joke that was going to cause tears, not laughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆★★★★★★★: Maugham surprised me</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/maugham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:04:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/maugham/</guid>
      <description>Everytime I picked Somerset Maugham&amp;rsquo;s books, two thoughts simultaneously would occur to me: the books were heavy and thick, and the print was too small. Consequently, I kept thinking, maybe when I find a better print, or when I have time.
A few days ago and quite accidentally, I ran into one of his short stories &amp;ldquo;A Friend in Need&amp;rdquo;. Now, normally, were I a somewhat-educated person, I would not have understood it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Pointlessness?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</guid>
      <description>In the introduction to Tristam Shandy&amp;rsquo;s Penguin edition, Christopher Ricks writes:
“Tristram Shandy is the greatest shaggy-dog story in the language&amp;hellip;.But there were voices saying that the book was obscene, or pointless, or deficient in everything that a novel ought to provide. The fact that pointlessness was one of Sterne’s points, that he was out to flout and taunt humdrum expectations – this meant little.”
Ricks calls the the sublimeness of literary art and its moral purpose a mere &amp;lsquo;humdrum expectations&amp;rsquo; and goes on to prattle, like Sterne, for several pages basically saying nothing at all meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆★★★★★★★: Matsumoto&#39;s Ruby Book</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 17:45:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</guid>
      <description>There are not many good technical books, but Matsumoto&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ruby Programming Language&amp;rdquo;, co-authored with Flanagan, stands out as one of best examples of technical writing.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why:
The writing is succinct without being abstrusely terse. It&amp;rsquo;s clear without being simplistic. The sentences are fluff-free and the meanings are conveyed clearly, like a good Ruby program. Consider this excerpt for example from page 75:
Every object has a well-defined class in Ruby, and that class never changes during the lifetime of the object.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
