<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 12:47:35 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is programming?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whatis_progr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whatis_progr/</guid>
      <description>Programming is fundamentally about abstraction - finding ways to simplify and automate complex tasks by breaking them into logical sequences of instructions. At its core, it is the pursuit of developing structured languages to bridge the gap between human cognition and machine execution.
The genius of programming lies in designing pragmatic artificial languages to achieve practical ends. We compose scripts in Ruby, sequences in Python, services in Scala, queries in SQL, rules in Prolog - each language a spell to conjure utility from silicon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perpetuation of ignorance</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an article written by a certain developer praising a certain software engineering book. But there were two problems. While the engineer seemed competent enough, and the book famous enough (it&amp;rsquo;s like Shakespeare, everyone claims it&amp;rsquo;s a masteriece but nobody seems to have read or finished it), the book has serious problems and the engineer was unaware that he was unaware of those problems.
This is how ignorance is perpetuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A To-Do app in Vlang</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/todo-app-in-vlang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:06:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/todo-app-in-vlang/</guid>
      <description>V language, also known as Vlang promises C&amp;rsquo;s speed, Rust&amp;rsquo;s safety, Go&amp;rsquo;s syntax. However, there is only one Vlang book avaiable from Packt and even that is simply listing language features&amp;ndash;a mere simpler documentation.
In this tutorial, I provide a real-world practical example: a command-line to-do app.
Audience:
Students and enthusiasts who have learned some programming but don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do next. They taught you to draw shapes, now draw the owl!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Python VSCode/Mac?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/python-on-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 17:33:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/python-on-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Legend Potential Audience:
Learners wanting to use a free but industrial-grade Python IDE on a Mac. Anyone having trouble using Python on Visual Studio Code because it &amp;lsquo;won&amp;rsquo;t run&amp;rsquo;. Why Mac? Unless you are Jabba, the Meister Programmer, I advise all learners to use MacOS for the smoothest possible journey in their quest to become programmers.
That&amp;rsquo;s because at its heart, MacOS is simply a flavor of Unix and you can&amp;rsquo;t do serious programming on Windows&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s a fact acknowledged by Microsoft, too (hence their providing the WSL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is difficult good?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</guid>
      <description>Among programmers and even common people in general, I feel there&amp;rsquo;s an implicit consensus that &amp;lsquo;difficult is good&amp;rsquo;. I got this idea when reading a book review, where the reviewer had implied that the book was worth reading because it was difficult.
Words are dangerous things if misused. Especially as experiences are subjective, and words reflect those experiences. So you and I might both use the word &amp;lsquo;difficult&amp;rsquo;, yet our subjective understanding of the term might vary too much to even be considered the same word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hobbit</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 23:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</guid>
      <description>I think what most people who don&amp;rsquo;t read don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that reading is a more active process than watching movie because your own imagination creates &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo; in the deep-end of the mind.
This is exactly why, at least for me, watching the movie then reading the book, is akin to ruining the reading experience.
And with an exception or two, the books are always way, way better than the movies based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Qur&#39;aan&#39;s Translations</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 14:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</guid>
      <description>I learned Qur&amp;rsquo;aanic Arabic (as a foreign language&amp;ndash;at the local mosque) when I was eight years old. But then decades had to pass when, after learning a great deal of worldly things, I am now feeling ready to truly study our Noble Book, and while I am brushing up on my classical Arabic, in the meantime, I wanted to find an English translation that was not deviating from the original in any sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Lisp is horrible</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:23:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</guid>
      <description>This is a first post in LR category&amp;ndash;Language Review&amp;ndash;where I will factually opine on various programming languages. And today&amp;rsquo;s victim is Lisp.
Or first, let me say the emperor has no clothes, or Scheme is an awful language.
I mean, not only it is an awful first language to teach beginners, or to self-learn on your own, but also in general, as a programming language in 2023, it is not as great as it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Object-oriented in &#39;Twin Peaks&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 13:12:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in the CR&amp;ndash;Code Review&amp;ndash;series. I hit upon the idea after I found this interesting discussion regarding Swift playgrounds, book 2 (Let&amp;rsquo;s Code 2), chapter named &amp;lsquo;Twin Peaks&amp;rsquo; in Scrabtree&amp;rsquo;s website, where he lamented his very long solution compared to Samantha&amp;rsquo;s shorter solution.
The purpose of this CR is to bring learners&amp;rsquo; attention to an interesting thing about object orientation: objects can be interdependent even if they were instantiated independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception: What on earth?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</guid>
      <description>In this essay, I am going to rant about Inception.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t think I watched it. I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to go beyond 17 minutes (out of 2+ hours). I think 17 minutes is enough to decide whether it is rubbish or not. In my opinion, it is a rubbish of the most interesting sort.
But how can it be? Out of 16000 reviews on Amazon, 95% are five- and four-star.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
