<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:42:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BR: Middlemarch</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/11/br-middlemarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:42:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/11/br-middlemarch/</guid>
      <description>Middlemarch by
George Eliot A book that was lauded (by Woolf) as the only British novel written for grownups. I dislike Woolf and I am not even sure why. There&amp;rsquo;s something off-putting in how her name, in combination with titles of some of her works, is perceived by me.
But I also disliked &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; without knowing exactly why. That was a long time ago, well before I knew it was a &amp;lsquo;she&amp;rsquo; and not a &amp;lsquo;he&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; was a pseudonym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BR: Where Evil Resides</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/10/br-where-evil-resides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 20:19:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/10/br-where-evil-resides/</guid>
      <description>Where Evil Resides by
Clifford Simak (BR: Book Review)
Recently managed to go through Simak&amp;rsquo;s fantasy title: Where Evil Resides, which made me wonder why a writer like Simak became famous in the first place? But again I see morons like Updike and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me: not all readers are intelligent enough to know what they should be reading.
Simak is nothing special. The story is flat, the characteras uni-dimensional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BR: Darker than Amber</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/06/br-darker-than-amber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 08:28:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/06/br-darker-than-amber/</guid>
      <description>Darker than Amber John Macdonald (BR: Book Review)
Don&amp;rsquo;t know what the fuss is all about. I read the reviews which were glowing, but the book didn&amp;rsquo;t deliver on those reviews.
The problem is that MacDonald is confused. He mixes his own conflated view of morality in the context of a poorly-constructed detective story, and the outcome is mangled mess of opinion and long, boring descriptions of rooms and furniture, with a few sleaze quirks thrown here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howdy Ruby!</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/good_ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/good_ruby/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 0: Ruby Shines Introduction
This book teaches both intermediate programming and intermediate Ruby: no ruby background is assumed, though.
A typical learner would be someone who has finished programming 101 in any language (say, Chris Pine&amp;rsquo;s Learn to Program because it uses Ruby), or learned some programming here and there&amp;ndash;Youtube?&amp;ndash;but now wants to consolidate their gains and go to the next level.
Pedagogical model
Or how I teach. Please the introduction in my other book, to Julia, for a deeper discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Julia?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/hello_julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/hello_julia/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 0: The Elegant Julia Introduction
This is the chapter zero of my upcoming programming in Julia textbook. The digital-only book assumes no pre-requisites, but moves at a rather fast pace (no fluff, no stories or random opinions about author, no discussion of how computers work or any historical references), all the while avoiding any irrational jumps, the confusing jargon overload, the incomplete information, the flawed pedagogy, or the boring handwaving so typical in so (unfortunately) many programming books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/about/</guid>
      <description>Beyond childhood, youth, and the associated tribulations, I divide my life so far into three periods. The golden period, the dreamy period, and the period of reality.
In the golden period, which lasted nearly 15 years, I was a professor of mathematics, social and natural sciences at several universities in East Asia.
In the dreamy period, I stopped teaching and entered the land of programming. The teacher and the programmer are still a part of me, even though I have entered the stage of reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
