<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 21:05:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Girl With The...</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 21:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</guid>
      <description>As it is, Larsson&amp;rsquo;s The girl with the dragon tattoo has nearly 31000 reviews, 68% of them five-star. This book crossed paths with me on and off several times since 2010, but my instinctual response would always be: &amp;lsquo;ahhh? no.&amp;rsquo;.
IN 2023, however, I had no other books to read in the toilet, so I decided to settle the matter once and for all. If it&amp;rsquo;s such a super-thriller people kept raving about, then there was going to be only one way to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perpetuation of ignorance</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an article written by a certain developer praising a certain software engineering book. But there were two problems. While the engineer seemed competent enough, and the book famous enough (it&amp;rsquo;s like Shakespeare, everyone claims it&amp;rsquo;s a masteriece but nobody seems to have read or finished it), the book has serious problems and the engineer was unaware that he was unaware of those problems.
This is how ignorance is perpetuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is difficult good?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</guid>
      <description>Among programmers and even common people in general, I feel there&amp;rsquo;s an implicit consensus that &amp;lsquo;difficult is good&amp;rsquo;. I got this idea when reading a book review, where the reviewer had implied that the book was worth reading because it was difficult.
Words are dangerous things if misused. Especially as experiences are subjective, and words reflect those experiences. So you and I might both use the word &amp;lsquo;difficult&amp;rsquo;, yet our subjective understanding of the term might vary too much to even be considered the same word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hobbit</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 23:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</guid>
      <description>I think what most people who don&amp;rsquo;t read don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that reading is a more active process than watching movie because your own imagination creates &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo; in the deep-end of the mind.
This is exactly why, at least for me, watching the movie then reading the book, is akin to ruining the reading experience.
And with an exception or two, the books are always way, way better than the movies based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Qur&#39;aan&#39;s Translations</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 14:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</guid>
      <description>I learned Qur&amp;rsquo;aanic Arabic (as a foreign language&amp;ndash;at the local mosque) when I was eight years old. But then decades had to pass when, after learning a great deal of worldly things, I am now feeling ready to truly study our Noble Book, and while I am brushing up on my classical Arabic, in the meantime, I wanted to find an English translation that was not deviating from the original in any sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Lisp is horrible</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:23:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</guid>
      <description>This is a first post in LR category&amp;ndash;Language Review&amp;ndash;where I will factually opine on various programming languages. And today&amp;rsquo;s victim is Lisp.
Or first, let me say the emperor has no clothes, or Scheme is an awful language.
I mean, not only it is an awful first language to teach beginners, or to self-learn on your own, but also in general, as a programming language in 2023, it is not as great as it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Object-oriented in &#39;Twin Peaks&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 13:12:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in the CR&amp;ndash;Code Review&amp;ndash;series. I hit upon the idea after I found this interesting discussion regarding Swift playgrounds, book 2 (Let&amp;rsquo;s Code 2), chapter named &amp;lsquo;Twin Peaks&amp;rsquo; in Scrabtree&amp;rsquo;s website, where he lamented his very long solution compared to Samantha&amp;rsquo;s shorter solution.
The purpose of this CR is to bring learners&amp;rsquo; attention to an interesting thing about object orientation: objects can be interdependent even if they were instantiated independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception: What on earth?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</guid>
      <description>In this essay, I am going to rant about Inception.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t think I watched it. I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to go beyond 17 minutes (out of 2+ hours). I think 17 minutes is enough to decide whether it is rubbish or not. In my opinion, it is a rubbish of the most interesting sort.
But how can it be? Out of 16000 reviews on Amazon, 95% are five- and four-star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubbishing Ayn Rand</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/ayn-rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 22:48:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/ayn-rand/</guid>
      <description>Today, the victim of my incisive criticism is Ayn Rand (or more accurtately, Alissa Zinovievna Rosenbaum). Now, a discerning thinker might object: but how can you criticize someone you haven&amp;rsquo;t read? Our answer is: do we need to befriend someone whose manners in the first few minutes of our acquaintance repulsed us? Time is gold, so a few paragraphs illustrating her thoughts would provide enough ammunition for a full-scale rubbishing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middlemarch</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/middlemarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:42:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/middlemarch/</guid>
      <description>Middlemarch by
George Eliot A book that was lauded (by Woolf) as the only British novel written for grownups. I dislike Woolf and I am not even sure why. There&amp;rsquo;s something off-putting in how her name, in combination with titles of some of her works, is perceived by me.
But I also disliked &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; without knowing exactly why. That was a long time ago, well before I knew it was a &amp;lsquo;she&amp;rsquo; and not a &amp;lsquo;he&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; was a pseudonym.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
