<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 08:28:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hi</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/05/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 08:28:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/posts/2022/05/hi/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post. More coming soon&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Julia?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/hello_julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/hello_julia/</guid>
      <description>﷽
This is the first and free chapter of my upcoming programming in Julia textbook. The book assumes no pre-requisites, but moves at a fast pace, all the while avoiding any irrational jumps, the confusing jargon overload, or the boring handwaving so typical in many programming books.
We use Julia for two main reasons: it is a good teaching language, but also an important real-world-ready new language, which boasts C-like speed, Kotlin-like safety, Ruby-like flexibility and programmer-happiness, A touch of Lispiness, Pythonesque clarity and terseness (even clearer than Python), and Matlab-like quant powers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/about/</guid>
      <description>﷽
Beyond childhood, youth, and the associated tribulations, I divide my life so far into three periods. The golden period, the dreamy period, and the period of reality.
In the golden period, which lasted nearly 15 years, I was a professor of mathematics, social and natural sciences at several universities in East Asia.
In the dreamy period, I stopped teaching and entered the land of programming. The teacher and the programmer are still a part of me, even though I have entered the stage of reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
