<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:04:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maugham surprised me</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/maugham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:04:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/maugham/</guid>
      <description>Everytime I picked Somerset Maugham&amp;rsquo;s books, two thoughts simultaneously would occur to me: the books were heavy and thick, and the print was too small. Consequently, I kept thinking, maybe when I find a better print, or when I have time.
A few days ago and quite accidentally, I ran into one of his short stories &amp;ldquo;A Friend in Need&amp;rdquo;. Now, normally, were I a somewhat-educated person, I would not have understood it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Pointlessness?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</guid>
      <description>In the introduction to Tristam Shandy&amp;rsquo;s Penguin edition, Christopher Ricks writes:
“Tristram Shandy is the greatest shaggy-dog story in the language&amp;hellip;.But there were voices saying that the book was obscene, or pointless, or deficient in everything that a novel ought to provide. The fact that pointlessness was one of Sterne’s points, that he was out to flout and taunt humdrum expectations – this meant little.”
Ricks calls the the sublimeness of literary art and its moral purpose a mere &amp;lsquo;humdrum expectations&amp;rsquo; and goes on to prattle, like Sterne, for several pages basically saying nothing at all meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10/10: Matsumoto&#39;s Ruby Book</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 17:45:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</guid>
      <description>There are not many good technical books, but Matsumoto&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ruby Programming Language&amp;rdquo;, co-authored with Flanagan, stands out as one of best examples of technical writing.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why:
The writing is succinct without being abstrusely terse. It&amp;rsquo;s clear without being simplistic. The sentences are fluff-free and the meanings are conveyed clearly, like a good Ruby program. Consider this excerpt for example from page 75:
Every object has a well-defined class in Ruby, and that class never changes during the lifetime of the object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Allah (ج) _need_ our praise?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:37:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</guid>
      <description>Missy A few months ago I found a poor kitty who was merely skin and bones, but most probably, she had been someone&amp;rsquo;s discarded or abandoned pet because she was not feral; she was friendly and let me pet her. She seemed to have a lot of health issues, so I took her to the vet, where, for some strange reason, she began hyperventilating:
It was heartbreaking but I was not going to give up on her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0/10: The Girl With The...</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 21:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</guid>
      <description>As it is, Larsson&amp;rsquo;s The girl with the dragon tattoo has nearly 31000 reviews, 68% of them five-star. This book crossed paths with me on and off several times since 2010, but my instinctual response would always be: &amp;lsquo;ahhh? no.&amp;rsquo;.
IN 2023, however, I had no other books to read in the toilet, so I decided to settle the matter once and for all. If it&amp;rsquo;s such a super-thriller people kept raving about, then there was going to be only one way to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perpetuation of ignorance</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an article written by a certain developer praising a certain software engineering book. But there were two problems. While the engineer seemed competent enough, and the book famous enough (it&amp;rsquo;s like Shakespeare, everyone claims it&amp;rsquo;s a masteriece but nobody seems to have read or finished it), the book has serious problems and the engineer was unaware that he was unaware of those problems.
This is how ignorance is perpetuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is difficult good?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</guid>
      <description>Among programmers and even common people in general, I feel there&amp;rsquo;s an implicit consensus that &amp;lsquo;difficult is good&amp;rsquo;. I got this idea when reading a book review, where the reviewer had implied that the book was worth reading because it was difficult.
Words are dangerous things if misused. Especially as experiences are subjective, and words reflect those experiences. So you and I might both use the word &amp;lsquo;difficult&amp;rsquo;, yet our subjective understanding of the term might vary too much to even be considered the same word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4/10: The Hobbit</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 23:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</guid>
      <description>I think what most people who don&amp;rsquo;t read don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that reading is a more active process than watching movie because your own imagination creates &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo; in the deep-end of the mind.
This is exactly why, at least for me, watching the movie then reading the book, is akin to ruining the reading experience.
And with an exception or two, the books are always way, way better than the movies based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Qur&#39;aan&#39;s Translations</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 14:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</guid>
      <description>I learned Qur&amp;rsquo;aanic Arabic (as a foreign language&amp;ndash;at the local mosque) when I was eight years old. But then decades had to pass when, after learning a great deal of worldly things, I am now feeling ready to truly study our Noble Book, and while I am brushing up on my classical Arabic, in the meantime, I wanted to find an English translation that was not deviating from the original in any sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Lisp is horrible</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:23:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</guid>
      <description>This is a first post in LR category&amp;ndash;Language Review&amp;ndash;where I will factually opine on various programming languages. And today&amp;rsquo;s victim is Lisp.
Or first, let me say the emperor has no clothes, or Scheme is an awful language.
I mean, not only it is an awful first language to teach beginners, or to self-learn on your own, but also in general, as a programming language in 2023, it is not as great as it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
