<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:22:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆★★★★★★★: PKD&#39;s The Adjustment Team</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/adjustment_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:22:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/adjustment_team/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while. Around eight months! But I&amp;rsquo;ve been through a lot in these eight months. I struggled with death only five months ago. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details here, but suffice it to say that I survived my Black Swan and I&amp;rsquo;m here again.
And back on track. Out of pure randomness, I ran into PKD&amp;rsquo;s short story &amp;ldquo;The Adjustment Team&amp;rdquo; which was intriguing and interesting. The scenery was described quite artistically, and only some of the characters were properly described, such as the old man with &amp;lsquo;his faded blue eyes mild&amp;ndash; a deep, ancient mildness that made the Clerk tremble even more&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Advantages of ADHD</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:26:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/adhd/</guid>
      <description>As an empath and a left-handed person who thinks he&amp;rsquo;s ADHD, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a stage in my life now, that looking at someone&amp;rsquo;s photo evokes feelings in my mind, that usually if not always, prove accurate.
I need to establish my qualifications first, so that my essay makes sense. I only became conscious or discovered the fact that I am an empath, in 2022. That means, for nearly four decades, I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of a sort of power in my mind, which both fascinated me and irritated those who were on the receiving end of my estimation of their mental states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆f: Herbert&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:40:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/dune/</guid>
      <description>Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s over.
But was it worth it? And why did I put up with it?
On Amazon, Dune has 99000 or so reviews, 97% of them five-star. I had to read this stupid book just in the interest of science, to see whether I should trust a large number of positive reviews in 2024.
It turns out, my poor opinion of this book is also, indirectly, an indictment of the intellects of those people who found the book worth five stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆★★★★★★★★★: Gogol&#39;s Diary of a Madman</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 14:47:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</guid>
      <description>Before reading a translated work, I often find as many translations as I can in order to choose the best. To me, the best means close to the original in both how words must have sounded in the original, but also rendering it in English in such a way that it should, by itself, have its own literary merits in English.
Translations of foreign novels rare rarely loyal but everytime I find a good translation, it confirms my hunch that the translator must be a writer and an artist of a high caliber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break into C#</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/4-break-into-c#/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:34:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/4-break-into-c#/</guid>
      <description>The pre-requisite for this chapter is &amp;lsquo;Break into Ruby&amp;rsquo;.
Do you think the program makes sense even though you&amp;rsquo;re new to C#? The aim here is to introduce you to just enough C# to let you decide whether it&amp;rsquo;s worth learning.
(If you want to download and try the game on your computer, head on to my github.)
1using System; 2using System.Collections.Generic; 3 4public class Program 5{ 6 static void Main() 7 { 8 var deck = new Deck(); 9 var playerHand = new Hand(); 10 var dealerHand = new Hand(); 11 12 playerHand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hackernews is a 1984</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 11:39:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</guid>
      <description>I occasionally read Y Combinator&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Hackernews&amp;rsquo; but each time I do, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded how it resembles Winston&amp;rsquo;s world in the novel 1984.
My visits are programming related; I want to know what new developments have been occurring in the programming world. Occasionally it will also serve as a news aggregator in general. To be fair, to this end, it serves a useful niche, and I will continue visiting the site for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APL is for the intelligent</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:28:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</guid>
      <description>Why is APL the language of the future, even though it is roughly 50 years old? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t it take off like C did? To answer this, we need to delve into probability and intelligence.
The problem with probability is that things that seem non-random or planned may actually be random (Tarasov, 1990), whereas things that seem random, may, sometimes be deterministic or an outcome of some emergent state (where the interaction of several elements and factors causes a new state to emerge: for instance, poverty is one such fuzzy emergent state).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆: Tears of joke: marginal functionalism</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:22:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</guid>
      <description>Did you understand the title of this essay? Probably not. Neither would I have understood, to be frank, were I not the author. That&amp;rsquo;s because when I was coming up with a title for this essay, which, in my mind, arose as an allergic reaction to the garbage that David Foster Wallace&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;The Infinite Jest&amp;rdquo; is, I was sort of trying to convey the idea that I was going to write an essay about the fact that some people among us are merely marginally functional&amp;ndash;functional enough to be considered legally sane&amp;ndash;but otherwise are actually seriously mentally ill, and that, this was a joke that was going to cause tears, not laughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Pointlessness?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</guid>
      <description>In the introduction to Tristam Shandy&amp;rsquo;s Penguin edition, Christopher Ricks writes:
“Tristram Shandy is the greatest shaggy-dog story in the language&amp;hellip;.But there were voices saying that the book was obscene, or pointless, or deficient in everything that a novel ought to provide. The fact that pointlessness was one of Sterne’s points, that he was out to flout and taunt humdrum expectations – this meant little.”
Ricks calls the the sublimeness of literary art and its moral purpose a mere &amp;lsquo;humdrum expectations&amp;rsquo; and goes on to prattle, like Sterne, for several pages basically saying nothing at all meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆★★★★★★★: Matsumoto&#39;s Ruby Book</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 17:45:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</guid>
      <description>There are not many good technical books, but Matsumoto&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ruby Programming Language&amp;rdquo;, co-authored with Flanagan, stands out as one of best examples of technical writing.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why:
The writing is succinct without being abstrusely terse. It&amp;rsquo;s clear without being simplistic. The sentences are fluff-free and the meanings are conveyed clearly, like a good Ruby program. Consider this excerpt for example from page 75:
Every object has a well-defined class in Ruby, and that class never changes during the lifetime of the object.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
