<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:06:52 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A To-Do app in Vlang</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/cr-vlangapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:06:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/cr-vlangapp/</guid>
      <description>V language, also known as Vlang promises C&amp;rsquo;s speed, Rust&amp;rsquo;s safety, Go&amp;rsquo;s syntax. However, there is only one Vlang book avaiable from Packt and even that is simply listing language features&amp;ndash;a mere simpler documentation.
In this booklet, I provide a real-world practical example: a command-line to-do app.
Audience:
Students and enthusiasts who have learned some programming but don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do next. They taught you to draw shapes, now draw the owl!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howdy Ruby!</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/programming-201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/programming-201/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 0: Ruby Shines Introduction
This book teaches both intermediate programming and intermediate Ruby: no ruby background is assumed, though.
A typical learner would be someone who has finished programming 101 in any language (say, Chris Pine&amp;rsquo;s Learn to Program because it uses Ruby), or learned some programming here and there&amp;ndash;Youtube?&amp;ndash;but now wants to consolidate their gains and go to the next level.
Pedagogical model
Or how I teach. Please the introduction in my other book, to Julia, for a deeper discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Julia?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/programming-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/books/programming-101/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 0: The Elegant Julia Introduction
This is the chapter zero of my upcoming programming in Julia textbook. The digital-only book assumes no pre-requisites, but moves at a rather fast pace (no fluff, no stories or random opinions about author, no discussion of how computers work or any historical references), all the while avoiding any irrational jumps, the confusing jargon overload, the incomplete information, the flawed pedagogy, or the boring handwaving so typical in so (unfortunately) many programming books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
