<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:40:17 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆f: Herbert&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:40:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/dune/</guid>
      <description>Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s over.
But was it worth it? And why did I put up with it?
On Amazon, Dune has 99000 or so reviews, 97% of them five-star. I had to read this stupid book just in the interest of science, to see whether I should trust a large number of positive reviews in 2024.
It turns out, my poor opinion of this book is also, indirectly, an indictment of the intellects of those people who found the book worth five stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆★★★★★★★★★: Gogol&#39;s Diary of a Madman</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 14:47:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/diary_of_madman/</guid>
      <description>Before reading a translated work, I often find as many translations as I can in order to choose the best. To me, the best means close to the original in both how words must have sounded in the original, but also rendering it in English in such a way that it should, by itself, have its own literary merits in English.
Translations of foreign novels rare rarely loyal but everytime I find a good translation, it confirms my hunch that the translator must be a writer and an artist of a high caliber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆: Tears of joke: marginal functionalism</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:22:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_infinite_joke/</guid>
      <description>Did you understand the title of this essay? Probably not. Neither would I have understood, to be frank, were I not the author. That&amp;rsquo;s because when I was coming up with a title for this essay, which, in my mind, arose as an allergic reaction to the garbage that David Foster Wallace&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;The Infinite Jest&amp;rdquo; is, I was sort of trying to convey the idea that I was going to write an essay about the fact that some people among us are merely marginally functional&amp;ndash;functional enough to be considered legally sane&amp;ndash;but otherwise are actually seriously mentally ill, and that, this was a joke that was going to cause tears, not laughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆★★★★★★★: Matsumoto&#39;s Ruby Book</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 17:45:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the_ruby_book/</guid>
      <description>There are not many good technical books, but Matsumoto&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ruby Programming Language&amp;rdquo;, co-authored with Flanagan, stands out as one of best examples of technical writing.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why:
The writing is succinct without being abstrusely terse. It&amp;rsquo;s clear without being simplistic. The sentences are fluff-free and the meanings are conveyed clearly, like a good Ruby program. Consider this excerpt for example from page 75:
Every object has a well-defined class in Ruby, and that class never changes during the lifetime of the object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆: Larsson&#39;s The Girl With...</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 21:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-girl-with-the/</guid>
      <description>As it is, Larsson&amp;rsquo;s The girl with the dragon tattoo has nearly 31000 reviews, 68% of them five-star. This book crossed paths with me on and off several times since 2010, but my instinctual response would always be: &amp;lsquo;ahhh? no.&amp;rsquo;.
IN 2023, however, I had no other books to read in the toilet, so I decided to settle the matter once and for all. If it&amp;rsquo;s such a super-thriller people kept raving about, then there was going to be only one way to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆★★★: Tolkien&#39;s Hobbit</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 23:05:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/the-hobbit/</guid>
      <description>I think what most people who don&amp;rsquo;t read don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that reading is a more active process than watching movie because your own imagination creates &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo; in the deep-end of the mind.
This is exactly why, at least for me, watching the movie then reading the book, is akin to ruining the reading experience.
And with an exception or two, the books are always way, way better than the movies based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆: Ayn Rand&#39;s every book</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/ayn-rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 22:48:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/ayn-rand/</guid>
      <description>Today, the victim of my incisive criticism is Ayn Rand. Now, a discerning thinker might object: but how can you criticize someone you haven&amp;rsquo;t read? Our answer is: do we need to befriend someone whose manners in the first few minutes of our acquaintance repulsed us? Time is gold, so a few paragraphs illustrating her thoughts would provide enough ammunition for a full-scale rubbishing.
Here is a golden one. In the preface to her Fountainhead, she wrote:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆★★★: Eliot&#39;s Middlemarch</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/middlemarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:42:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/middlemarch/</guid>
      <description>Middlemarch by
George Eliot A book that was lauded (by Woolf) as the only British novel written for grownups. I dislike Woolf and I am not even sure why. There&amp;rsquo;s something off-putting in how her name, in combination with titles of some of her works, is perceived by me.
But I also disliked &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; without knowing exactly why. That was a long time ago, well before I knew it was a &amp;lsquo;she&amp;rsquo; and not a &amp;lsquo;he&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;ldquo;George Eliot&amp;rdquo; was a pseudonym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆★: Simak&#39;s Where Evil Resides</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/-where-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 20:19:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/-where-evil/</guid>
      <description>Where Evil Resides by
Clifford Simak (BR: Book Review)
Recently managed to go through Simak&amp;rsquo;s fantasy title: Where Evil Resides, which made me wonder why a writer like Simak became famous in the first place? But again I see morons like Updike and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me: not all readers are intelligent enough to know what they should be reading.
Simak is nothing special. The story is flat, the characteras uni-dimensional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆★★: Macdonald&#39;s Darker than Amber</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/darker-than-amber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 08:28:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/reviews/darker-than-amber/</guid>
      <description>Darker than Amber John Macdonald Don&amp;rsquo;t know what the fuss is all about. I read the reviews which were glowing, but the book didn&amp;rsquo;t deliver on those reviews.
The problem is that MacDonald is confused. He mixes his own conflated view of morality in the context of a poorly-constructed detective story, and the outcome is mangled mess of opinion and long, boring descriptions of rooms and furniture, with a few sleaze quirks thrown here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
