<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:06:52 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A To-Do app in Vlang</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/todo-app-in-vlang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:06:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/todo-app-in-vlang/</guid>
      <description>V language, also known as Vlang promises C&amp;rsquo;s speed, Rust&amp;rsquo;s safety, Go&amp;rsquo;s syntax. However, there is only one Vlang book avaiable from Packt and even that is simply listing language features&amp;ndash;a mere simpler documentation.
In this tutorial, I provide a real-world practical example: a command-line to-do app.
Audience:
Students and enthusiasts who have learned some programming but don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do next. They taught you to draw shapes, now draw the owl!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Python VSCode/Mac?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/python-on-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 17:33:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/python-on-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Legend Potential Audience:
Learners wanting to use a free but industrial-grade Python IDE on a Mac. Anyone having trouble using Python on Visual Studio Code because it &amp;lsquo;won&amp;rsquo;t run&amp;rsquo;. Why Mac? Unless you are Jabba, the Meister Programmer, I advise all learners to use MacOS for the smoothest possible journey in their quest to become programmers.
That&amp;rsquo;s because at its heart, MacOS is simply a flavor of Unix and you can&amp;rsquo;t do serious programming on Windows&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s a fact acknowledged by Microsoft, too (hence their providing the WSL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Lisp is horrible</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:23:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/why-lisp-is-horrible/</guid>
      <description>This is a first post in LR category&amp;ndash;Language Review&amp;ndash;where I will factually opine on various programming languages. And today&amp;rsquo;s victim is Lisp.
Or first, let me say the emperor has no clothes, or Scheme is an awful language.
I mean, not only it is an awful first language to teach beginners, or to self-learn on your own, but also in general, as a programming language in 2023, it is not as great as it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Object-oriented in &#39;Twin Peaks&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 13:12:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/tutorials/oop-in-swift-grounds/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in the CR&amp;ndash;Code Review&amp;ndash;series. I hit upon the idea after I found this interesting discussion regarding Swift playgrounds, book 2 (Let&amp;rsquo;s Code 2), chapter named &amp;lsquo;Twin Peaks&amp;rsquo; in Scrabtree&amp;rsquo;s website, where he lamented his very long solution compared to Samantha&amp;rsquo;s shorter solution.
The purpose of this CR is to bring learners&amp;rsquo; attention to an interesting thing about object orientation: objects can be interdependent even if they were instantiated independently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
