<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:04:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maugham surprised me</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/maugham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:04:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/maugham/</guid>
      <description>Everytime I picked Somerset Maugham&amp;rsquo;s books, two thoughts simultaneously would occur to me: the books were heavy and thick, and the print was too small. Consequently, I kept thinking, maybe when I find a better print, or when I have time. I didn&amp;rsquo;t outright reject his works as my gut feeling was pro-Maugham. And in such procrastination, several years passed&amp;hellip;.
But then, quite accidentally, I ran into one of his short stories &amp;ldquo;A Friend in Need&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Pointlessness?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</guid>
      <description>In the introduction to Tristam Shandy&amp;rsquo;s Penguin edition, Christopher Ricks writes:
“Tristram Shandy is the greatest shaggy-dog story in the language&amp;hellip;.But there were voices saying that the book was obscene, or pointless, or deficient in everything that a novel ought to provide. The fact that pointlessness was one of Sterne’s points, that he was out to flout and taunt humdrum expectations – this meant little.”
Ricks calls the the sublimeness of literary art and its moral purpose a mere &amp;lsquo;humdrum expectations&amp;rsquo; and goes on to prattle, like Sterne, for several pages basically saying nothing at all meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Allah (ج) _need_ our praise?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:37:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</guid>
      <description>Missy A few months ago I found a poor kitty who was merely skin and bones, but most probably, she had been someone&amp;rsquo;s discarded or abandoned pet because she was not feral; she was friendly and let me pet her. She seemed to have a lot of health issues, so I took her to the vet, where, for some strange reason, she began hyperventilating:
It was heartbreaking but I was not going to give up on her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perpetuation of ignorance</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an article written by a certain developer praising a certain software engineering book. But there were two problems. While the engineer seemed competent enough, and the book famous enough (it&amp;rsquo;s like Shakespeare, everyone claims it&amp;rsquo;s a masteriece but nobody seems to have read or finished it), the book has serious problems and the engineer was unaware that he was unaware of those problems.
This is how ignorance is perpetuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is difficult good?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</guid>
      <description>Among programmers and even common people in general, I feel there&amp;rsquo;s an implicit consensus that &amp;lsquo;difficult is good&amp;rsquo;. I got this idea when reading a book review, where the reviewer had implied that the book was worth reading because it was difficult.
Words are dangerous things if misused. Especially as experiences are subjective, and words reflect those experiences. So you and I might both use the word &amp;lsquo;difficult&amp;rsquo;, yet our subjective understanding of the term might vary too much to even be considered the same word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Qur&#39;aan&#39;s Translations</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 14:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</guid>
      <description>I learned Qur&amp;rsquo;aanic Arabic (as a foreign language&amp;ndash;at the local mosque) when I was eight years old. But then decades had to pass when, after learning a great deal of worldly things, I am now feeling ready to truly study our Noble Book, and while I am brushing up on my classical Arabic, in the meantime, I wanted to find an English translation that was not deviating from the original in any sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception: What on earth?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/inception-/</guid>
      <description>In this essay, I am going to rant about Inception.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t think I watched it. I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to go beyond 17 minutes (out of 2+ hours). I think 17 minutes is enough to decide whether it is rubbish or not. In my opinion, it is a rubbish of the most interesting sort.
But how can it be? Out of 16000 reviews on Amazon, 95% are five- and four-star.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
