<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Jan Savage</title>
    <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Jan Savage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:26:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Advantages of ADHD</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:26:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/adhd/</guid>
      <description>As an empath and a left-handed person who thinks he&amp;rsquo;s ADHD, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a stage in my life now, that looking at someone&amp;rsquo;s photo evokes feelings in my mind, that usually if not always, prove accurate.
I need to establish my qualifications first, so that my essay makes sense. I only became conscious or discovered the fact that I am an empath, in 2022. That means, for nearly four decades, I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of a sort of power in my mind, which both fascinated me and irritated those who were on the receiving end of my estimation of their mental states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hackernews is a 1984</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 11:39:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/hackernews/</guid>
      <description>I occasionally read Y Combinator&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Hackernews&amp;rsquo; but each time I do, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded how it resembles Winston&amp;rsquo;s world in the novel 1984.
My visits are programming related; I want to know what new developments have been occurring in the programming world. Occasionally it will also serve as a news aggregator in general. To be fair, to this end, it serves a useful niche, and I will continue visiting the site for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APL is for the intelligent</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:28:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whyapl/</guid>
      <description>Why is APL the language of the future, even though it is roughly 50 years old? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t it take off like C did? To answer this, we need to delve into probability and intelligence.
The problem with probability is that things that seem non-random or planned may actually be random (Tarasov, 1990), whereas things that seem random, may, sometimes be deterministic or an outcome of some emergent state (where the interaction of several elements and factors causes a new state to emerge: for instance, poverty is one such fuzzy emergent state).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Pointlessness?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/point_of_pointlessness/</guid>
      <description>In the introduction to Tristam Shandy&amp;rsquo;s Penguin edition, Christopher Ricks writes:
“Tristram Shandy is the greatest shaggy-dog story in the language&amp;hellip;.But there were voices saying that the book was obscene, or pointless, or deficient in everything that a novel ought to provide. The fact that pointlessness was one of Sterne’s points, that he was out to flout and taunt humdrum expectations – this meant little.”
Ricks calls the the sublimeness of literary art and its moral purpose a mere &amp;lsquo;humdrum expectations&amp;rsquo; and goes on to prattle, like Sterne, for several pages basically saying nothing at all meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Allah (ج) _need_ our praise?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:37:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/whypraise/</guid>
      <description>Missy A few months ago I found a poor kitty who was merely skin and bones, but most probably, she had been someone&amp;rsquo;s discarded or abandoned pet because she was not feral; she was friendly and let me pet her. She seemed to have a lot of health issues, so I took her to the vet, where, for some strange reason, she began hyperventilating:
It was heartbreaking but I was not going to give up on her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perpetuation of ignorance</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/perpetuation_igno/</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an article written by a certain developer praising a certain software engineering book. But there were two problems. While the engineer seemed competent enough, and the book famous enough (it&amp;rsquo;s like Shakespeare, everyone claims it&amp;rsquo;s a masteriece but nobody seems to have read or finished it), the book has serious problems and the engineer was unaware that he was unaware of those problems.
This is how ignorance is perpetuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is difficult good?</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:47:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/isdifficult_good/</guid>
      <description>Among programmers and even common people in general, I feel there&amp;rsquo;s an implicit consensus that &amp;lsquo;difficult is good&amp;rsquo;. I got this idea when reading a book review, where the reviewer had implied that the book was worth reading because it was difficult.
Words are dangerous things if misused. Especially as experiences are subjective, and words reflect those experiences. So you and I might both use the word &amp;lsquo;difficult&amp;rsquo;, yet our subjective understanding of the term might vary too much to even be considered the same word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Qur&#39;aan&#39;s Translations</title>
      <link>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 14:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dersavage.github.io/main/essays/noble-quran-translations/</guid>
      <description>I learned Qur&amp;rsquo;aanic Arabic (as a foreign language&amp;ndash;at the local mosque) when I was eight years old. But then decades had to pass when, after learning a great deal of worldly things, I am now feeling ready to truly study our Noble Book, and while I am brushing up on my classical Arabic, in the meantime, I wanted to find an English translation that was not deviating from the original in any sense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
